Tonight, they're calling the shots.
Coyote Ugly is a comedy, drama, music film directed by David McNally.
Graced with a velvet voice, 21-year-old Violet Sanford heads to New York to pursue her dream of becoming a songwriter only to find
her aspirations sidelined by the accolades and notoriety she receives at her "day" job as a barmaid at Coyote Ugly.
The "Coyotes" as they are affectionately called tantalize customers and the media alike with
their outrageous antics, making Coyote Ugly the watering hole for guys on the prowl.
Violet Sanford (Jersey), played by Piper Perabo.
Lil, played by Maria Bello.
Rachel, played by Bridget Moynahan.
Zoe, played by Tyra Banks.
Cammie, played by Izabella Miko.
Bill, played by John Goodman.
Coyote Ugly is a 2000 American comedy-drama film
based on the Coyote Ugly Saloon.
It was directed by David McNally, produced by Jerry Bruckheimer and Chad Oman, and written by Gina Wendkos and
an uncredited Kevin Smith, based on "The Muse of the Coyote Ugly Saloon" by Elizabeth Gilbert.
Set at the titular drinking establishment in New York City, the film stars Piper Perabo in her
breakthrough role, Adam Garcia, Maria Bello, Melanie Lynskey, and John Goodman.
The film received mostly negative reviews but was a box office
success nonetheless, grossing $113 million worldwide.
The film has become a cult classic over the years.
In 2020, Tyra Banks said that she had been lobbying the
original production team for a sequel for years.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.